ALEXEY SHTANKO

Android Developer | iOS Developer

Phone: +380688005548 Skype: shtankoksu Github: <u>Alexey Shtanko</u>

Email: adamluissean@gmail.com

Linkedin: <u>adamluissean</u>

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

More than 4 years of professional experience in mobile development for Android and iOS platforms. Strong knowledge of Kotlin and Java. Building native libraries for mobile clients, Android NDK expertise. Following Agile (Scrum) methodology principles. App Store and Google Play Market app delivering experience.

EDUCATION

BS, Kherson State University, Software Engineering 2011 - 2015

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bonsite LLC

Wezom Mobile

Junior Android Developer

May 2014 - Jul 2015

Mezom Mobile

Junior IOS Developer

Apr 2016 - Jul 2017

Middle Android Developer

Multimedia Nordic

Middle + Android Developer(Kotlin)

December 2018 - Present

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Kotlin, Swift

Databases: Sqlite(Android), Room(Android), Realm(Android/iOS)

Technical Tools: IntelliJ Idea, Android Studio, Xcode, AppCode, CMake

Technologies & Frameworks:

• OOP, MVVM, MVP, Design Patterns

• Cocoa, Swift, RxSwift, SnapKit, R.swift

• Android SDK, Retrofit, Picasso, OkHttp, Realm, GSON, Google Play Services, Clean Architecture, JUnit

Version Control Systems: Git

Build Tools: Maven, Gradle, Cocoa Pods, Fastlane

Development Environment & Bug Tracking Systems: Jira, Trello



RECENTLY COMPLETED PROJECTS

Fersk Fangst

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: Fersk Fangst is a market for buying and selling food and great service. The market

is free to use, and collects farmers, hunters and fishermen in the same place to sell their unique foods. You are also invited to contribute if you have food or

experiences you want to sell to others.

Position: Middle + Android developer

Technologies: Kotlin, Android, Retrofit, RxJava 2, Websockets

Roles:

• Development from scratch

Links: <u>Fersk Fangst on Google Play</u>

Social Network VPN Android Application

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: Yet another simple VPN client for Android. With an active service subscription,

user can create an encrypted and secure channel between devices and one of our

servers in over ten countries using VPN technology.

Position: Middle Android developer

Technologies: Java, Android, Kotlin, Retrofit, RxJava, Android NDK.

Roles:

• New features implementation

Custom UI creation

Legacy code support

Links: <u>Social Network VPN on Google Plav</u>

VPN Shield Android Application

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: A VPN client for Android. With an active service subscription, user can create an

encrypted and secure channel between devices and one of our servers in over ten

countries using VPN technology.

Position: Middle Android developer

Technologies: Java, Android, Kotlin, Retrofit, RxJava, Android NDK, Unit Testing, UI Testing.

Roles:

• New features implementation

Legacy code support

Links: <u>VPN Shield on Google Play</u>

Servolab Pro For Doctor Android Application

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: Android client for doctors. The application help doctors referring customers for

consultation, review, or further action. Doctor can view list of laboratories and find it on the map. Doctor have an opportunity to view description specific laboratory details(location, work time, website, phone number, route). Doctor have access to a large list of professional services for laboratories and clinics, detailed descriptions of analyzes, details and peculiarities of their conduct and patient training. The patient receives a referral from the doctor and independently chooses the labs in the application. The doctor sees when the analysis is done and remotely

receives the research results without visiting the client.

Position: Middle Android developer

Technologies: Android, Java, Kotlin, Firebase, Retrofit, RxJava, REST Api, Google Play

Services, Google Gson, Dagger, Clean Architecture, MVP, Unit Testing, UI

Testing.

Roles:

Maps module development

• Custom UI creation

Architecture design and development

• New features implementation

Links: <u>Servolab Pro on Google Play</u>

ULC Social Streaming iOS Application

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: A social network of live video broadcasts and games. User can play in simple

video game like rock-paper-scissors and streaming simultaneously. Also users can start two, three or four video sessions for talks with friends. Users can watch other live game or talk sessions. Application support game chat and simple friends chat.

Position: Junior iOS developer

Technologies: Swift, Realm, Open GLES, iOS Media API, Websockets.

Roles:

Auth module developmentMedia module development

• Custom UI creation

Video streaming module development

• Unity 3d game development and porting for iOS and Android

Links: <u>ULC on App Store</u>

ТРЦ Fabrika Android Application

Customer: Fabrika Shopping Mall Ukraine

Description: The application helps people to get information about differents shops and view

discounts, view interesting events and view photos and videos from this events.

Position: Junior Android developer

Technologies: Java, Android, Realm, Retrofit, RxJava.

Roles:

• Full stack development

Links: Available locally